Guide to the Linonian Society, Yale College, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Linonian Society, Yale College, records
1753-1870
RU 206
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
9.25
(22 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, secretary's records, treasurer's records, and librarian's records documenting society activities, membership, financial affairs, the society's founding, book collections, and other relevant activities.
Yale College (1718-1887). Linonian Society
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
The Linonian Literary Society was founded in 1753. All undergraduates were allowed to be members of the Linonian Society. The club provided students with a forum to debate, stage plays, and deliver poems, essays, and orations. The society disbanded in 1868.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, secretary"s records, treasurer's records, and librarian's records documenting society activities, membership, financial affairs, the society's founding, book collections, and other relevant activities.
General
Forms part of Yale Record Group 40 (YRG 40), Records of Yale clubs, societies, and organizations.
Arrangement
The records are arranged in four series: I. General Correspondence. II. Secretary's Records. III. Treasurer"s Records. IV. Librarian's Records; and subsequent accessions.
College students -- Societies, etc.; Debates and debating; Literature -- Societies, etc.; Oratory; Yale College (1718-1887) -- Students; Yale College (1718-1887). Linonian Society
- General Correspondence, 1841-1864; Series I
  - 1841-1846 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1847-1849 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1850-1852 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1853-1857 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1861-1864 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Secretary's Records, 1753-1870; Series II
  - General records: orations, disputes, compositions, constitution, list of members, library catalog, 1753 [1772-1802], undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Catalog of members
    - 1753-1797
      General
      See: box 2, folder 1
    - 1826-1851 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - 1839-1851 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - 1853-1865 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 1853-1870 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Constitutions
    - 1792-1825 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - 18th century
    - pre-1828, 1841 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - pre-1835 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - 1863 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - 1878 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Prudential Committee, 1858-1861 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Minutes
    - 1766-1767 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - 1768-1790 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - 1790-1797 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - 1797-1802 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - 1802-1811 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - 1811-1816 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - 1816-1822 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - 1822-1828 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - 1828-1834 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - 1834-1839 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - 1839-1842 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - 1842-1845 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - 1845-1849 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - 1849-1853 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - 1853-1863 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - 1855 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - 1863-1867 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Reports
    - 1851-1853 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - 1853 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Orations, Plays, Addresses, Debates
    - 1772-1802
  - Orations
    - 1772 Play: the Quixottish Philosopher by James H. Linsley (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - ca. 1814-1817 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Addresses
    - 1831 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - 1832 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Prize debates and announcements
    - 1851-1860, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Oversize
    - Minutes and lists of books in the library [bound photostatic copy], 1768-1791 (Box 8a)
    - Orations, dissertations, catalog of members, catalog of books [bound photostatic copy], 1753-1791
- Treasurer's Records, 1781-1870; Series III
  - Accounts (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - 1791 [fragment] (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - 1791-1822 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - 1822-1832 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Prudential Committee Accounts, 1833 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Debate Prizes, 1864-1866 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Financial Reports (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - 1819 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - 1846-1851 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - 1852-1857 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - 1859-1866 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - 1866-1870 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Bills and Receipts (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - 1795 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - 1810-1819 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - ca. 1820-1830 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - 1820-1824 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - 1825-1826 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - 1827-1829 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - 1830 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - 1831-1833 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - 1834-1835 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - 1836-1839 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - 1840 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - 1841 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - 1842-1845 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - 1846-1847 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - 1849 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - 1850-1851 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - 1853-1855 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - 1856-1857 (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - 1858 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - 1859 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - 1860 (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - 1861 (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - 1862 (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - 1863 (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - 1864 (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - 1865 (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - 1866 (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - 1867 (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - 1868 (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - n.d. (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Alumni Hall (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - Subscriptions, 1849-1861, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - Financial Obligation, 1853 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Balance Due, 1854 (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - Bills for Furnishings (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - Dues Ledgers (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - 1822-1825 (Box 12, Folder 45)
    - 1826-1832 (Box 12, Folder 46)
    - 1833-1838 (Box 12, Folder 47)
    - 1838-1842 (Box 12, Folder 48)
    - 1838-1846 (Box 12, Folder 49)
    - 1860-1867 (Box 12, Folder 50)
  - Tax Ledger, 1860 (Box 13, Folder 51)
- Librarian's Records, 1780-1866; Series IV
  - Catalogs of Books
    - Post-1785 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - ca. 1790 [see: series II minutes 1768-1790]
    - 1790 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - 1831-1834 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - 1834 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - post-1841 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - post-1850 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Shelf List, 1863 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Circulation Charges
    - 1807-1812? (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - 1822-1823 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - 1824-1826 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - 1828-1829 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - 1829-1830 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - 1830-1837 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - 1830-1831 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - 1831-1832 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - 1842-1845 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - 1845-1849 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - 1849-1853 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - 1860-1866 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Book Donations
    - Circa 1790
      See: series II, box 5, folder 13
    - 1825-1865 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Circa 1828-1833 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Accessions
    - Ca.1849 or later (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Bookplate, ca. 1780 (Box 20, Folder 23)
- Invitation to Linonion Ball, Accession 1994-A-093
  - Invitation to ball, 1785 (Box 1)